<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>global-state on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.axlight.com/tags/global-state/</link>
    <description>Recent content in global-state on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 22:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.axlight.com/tags/global-state/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Valtio Proxy State Works (React Part)</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-valtio-proxy-state-works-react-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 22:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-valtio-proxy-state-works-react-part/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the previous article, we explained how Valtio proxy state works. It tracks mutations of state and create immutable snapshot.
Let&amp;rsquo;s recap the API in vanilla part of Valtio.
// Create a new proxy state to detect mutations const state = proxy({ count: 0 }); // You can mutate it ++state.count; // Create a snapshot const snap1 = snapshot(state); // ---&amp;gt; { count: 1 }  // Mutate it again state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning React State Manager Jotai With 7GUIS Tasks</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/learning-react-state-manager-jotai-with-7guis-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 20:23:30 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/learning-react-state-manager-jotai-with-7guis-tasks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I stumbled upon 7GUIS tasks while reading XState Tutorials. This motivated me to challenge those 7 tasks with jotai.
It turned out that this would be a good resource to learn jotai. They are from basic tasks to advanced tasked, and you will see how they are implemented, occasionally magically.
It&amp;rsquo;s recommended to try it yourself first. If you succeed to implement it, then you can compare. Even if you fail, you can read and learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Valtio Proxy State Works (Vanilla Part)</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-valtio-proxy-state-works-vanilla-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 22:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-valtio-proxy-state-works-vanilla-part/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Valtio is a library for global state primarily for React. It&amp;rsquo;s originally modeled to match with useMutableSource API. However, it turns out it&amp;rsquo;s a novel API to add immutability to mutable state.
What is immutable state? JavaScript doesn&amp;rsquo;t support immutability as language, so it&amp;rsquo;s just a coding contract.
const immutableState1 = { count: 0, text: &amp;#39;hello&amp;#39; }; // update the state const immutableState2 = { ...immutableState1, count: immutableState1.count + 1 }; // update it again const immutableState3 = { .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Global State Libraries With React 18 Alpha Concurrent Rendering</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/testing-global-state-libraries-with-react-18-alpha-concurrent-rendering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 21:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/testing-global-state-libraries-with-react-18-alpha-concurrent-rendering/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The React team announced The Plan for React 18 with various features. Among them, concurrent rendering is one of my interests because I have been developing various global state libraries and there are known issues called &amp;ldquo;tearing&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;branching&amp;rdquo;.
Tearing is an undesirable behavior in which two components render with different values for same global state.
Branching is a desirable behavior in which a component renders with a stale value for a state in a transition update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing React Global State Library With Atom Abstraction</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/developing-react-global-state-library-with-atom-abstraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/developing-react-global-state-library-with-atom-abstraction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have been developing various global state libraries for React. For example:
 react-tracked react-hooks-global-state  My main motivation is to eliminate selector functions that are only required for render optimization. Render optimization here means it avoids extra re-renders. An extra re-render is a re-render process that produces the same view result as before.
Since Recoil is announced, I&amp;rsquo;m very interested in atom abstraction because it eliminates selector functions for render optimization and the API seems pretty intuitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redux in Worker: Off-main-thread Redux Reducers and Middleware</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/redux-in-worker-off-main-thread-redux-reducers-and-middleware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 20:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/redux-in-worker-off-main-thread-redux-reducers-and-middleware/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Redux is a framework-agnostic library for global state. It&amp;rsquo;s often used with React.
While I like the abstraction of Redux, React will introduce Concurrent Mode in the near future. If we want to get benefit of useTransition, state must be inside React to allow state branching. That means we can&amp;rsquo;t get the benefit with Redux.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing React Tracked for global state that allows state branching. It works well in Concurrent Mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steps to Develop Global State for React With Hooks Without Context</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/steps-to-develop-global-state-for-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 23:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/steps-to-develop-global-state-for-react/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Developing with React hooks is fun for me. I have been developing several libraries. The very first library was a library for global state. It&amp;rsquo;s naively called &amp;ldquo;react-hooks-global-state&amp;rdquo; which turns out to be too long to read.
The initial version of the library was published in Oct 2018. Time has passed since then, I learned a lot, and now v1.0.0 of the library is published.
https://github.com/dai-shi/react-hooks-global-state
This post shows simplified versions of the code step by step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Handle Async Actions for Global State With React Hooks and Context</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-to-handle-async-actions-for-global-state-with-react-hooks-and-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 23:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-to-handle-async-actions-for-global-state-with-react-hooks-and-context/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have been developing React Tracked, which is a library for global state with React Hooks and Context.
https://react-tracked.js.org
This is a small library and focuses on only one thing. It optimizes re-renders using state usage tracking. More technically, it uses Proxies to detect the usage in render, and only triggers re-renders if necessary.
Because of that, the usage of React Tracked is very straightforward. It is just like the normal useContext.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React Tracked Documentation Website with Docusaurus v2</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-tracked-documentation-website-with-docusaurus-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 23:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-tracked-documentation-website-with-docusaurus-v2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have been developing a React Hooks library called React Tracked. This is the library I put much effort lately as well as my other libraries.
https://github.com/dai-shi/react-tracked
This library solves a performance issue with React Context. For those who are interested in the fundamental problem, please take a look at the long issue.
What&amp;rsquo;s notable in this library is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide any new fancy features. You can simply replace Context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off-main-thread React Redux with Performance</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/off-main-thread-react-redux-with-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 11:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/off-main-thread-react-redux-with-performance/</guid>
      <description>Introduction It is said that Redux has been overused in some use cases and React context+hooks plays well in such use cases. While I agree with it, Redux should work well in some other situations. Redux should help developing larger apps with many developers. Various libraries in Redux ecosystem should accelerate development. There&amp;rsquo;s another situation in which Redux may help, and that is Web Workers.
A while back, Surma posted a nice blog post: React + Redux + Comlink = Off-main-thread</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 options to prevent extra rerenders with React context</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/4-options-to-prevent-extra-rerenders-with-react-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 21:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/4-options-to-prevent-extra-rerenders-with-react-context/</guid>
      <description>Introduction React context and useContext are very handy. You would have no problem using it while developing a small app. If the size of your app became non-trivial, you might experience some performance issues with regard to useContext. This is because useContext will trigger rerender whenever the context value is changed. This happens even if the part of the value is not used in render. This is by design. If useContext were to conditionally trigger rerenders, the hook would become non-composable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React hooks-oriented Redux coding pattern without thunks and action creators</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-hooks-oriented-redux-coding-pattern-without-thunks-and-action-creators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 10:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-hooks-oriented-redux-coding-pattern-without-thunks-and-action-creators/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I love Redux. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I like all parts of Redux ecosystem. Some people dislike Redux because of its boilerplate code. That&amp;rsquo;s sad. Boilerplate code is not from the Redux core, but from the ecosystem. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. Best practices are nice and I think the recent work of Redux Starter Kit is great. (Claps to Mark)
I think I have my own understanding of how to use Redux with React.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I developed a Concurrent Mode friendly library for React Redux</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-i-developed-a-concurrent-mode-friendly-library-for-react-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 23:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-i-developed-a-concurrent-mode-friendly-library-for-react-redux/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have been developing several React hooks libraries for months. In this post, I will explain why and how I developed a React Redux binding library with React hooks. The library is implemented to be concurrent mode friendly. Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss why it&amp;rsquo;s important and what&amp;rsquo;s the technique behind it.
React concurrent mode has not come yet, and all discussions are based on the current unstable behavior. Please note that when concurrent mode is released and best practice is researched, things may change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortless render optimization with state usage tracking with React hooks</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/effortless-render-optimization-with-state-usage-tracking-with-react-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 13:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/effortless-render-optimization-with-state-usage-tracking-with-react-hooks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction React useContext is very handy to avoid prop drilling. It can be used to define global state or shared state that multiple components in the tree can access.
However, useContext is not specifically designed for global state and there&amp;rsquo;s a caveat. Any change to context value propagates all useContext to re-render components.
This post shows some example code about the problem and the solution with state usage tracking.
Problem Let&amp;rsquo;s assume a person object as a state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use react-tracked: React hooks-oriented Todo List example</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-to-use-react-tracked-react-hooks-oriented-todo-list-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-to-use-react-tracked-react-hooks-oriented-todo-list-example/</guid>
      <description>Introduction React hooks have changed the way to compose components. This post will show an example which is very hooks-oriented.
We use two libraries: react-tracked and immer. While immer makes it easy to update state in an immutable way, react-tracked makes it easy to read state with tracking for optimization. Please check out the repo for more details.
https://github.com/dai-shi/react-tracked
The example we show is the one from Redux: Todo List</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is state usage tracking? A novel approach to intuitive and performant global state with React hooks and Proxy</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/what-is-state-usage-tracking-a-novel-approach-to-intuitive-and-performant-api-with-react-hooks-and-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 17:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/what-is-state-usage-tracking-a-novel-approach-to-intuitive-and-performant-api-with-react-hooks-and-proxy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction There are many libraries for global state with React hooks. React Redux also provides hooks API, which is very clean.
In general, I would avoid using global state. It would reduce the isolation of components. Multiple contexts should work fine for certain use cases.
But, what if we really need a global state.
Problem When a state is a non-trivial object, it&amp;rsquo;s not likely to use all properties of the object for one component to render.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super performant global state with React context and hooks</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/super-performant-global-state-with-react-context-and-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 23:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/super-performant-global-state-with-react-context-and-hooks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction There are many libraries to provide global state in React. React itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide such a feature, probably because separation of concerns is important and having global state naively is not idiomatic. However, in certain cases, having global state is good as long as it&amp;rsquo;s properly implemented. It&amp;rsquo;s likely that performance drops down compared to using non-global state (incl. multiple contexts).
This post introduces a library for global state with performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redux meets hooks for non-redux users: a small concrete example with reactive-react-redux</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/redux-meets-hooks-for-non-redux-users-a-small-concrete-example-with-reactive-react-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 23:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/redux-meets-hooks-for-non-redux-users-a-small-concrete-example-with-reactive-react-redux/</guid>
      <description>Introduction If you had already used Redux and loved it, you might not understand why people try using React context and hooks to replace Redux (a.k.a no Redux hype). For those who would think Redux DevTools Extension and middleware are nice to have, Redux and context + hooks are actually two options. Context + hooks is just fine to share state among components, however if apps get bigger, they are likely to require Redux or other similar solutions; otherwise they end up having many contexts that can&amp;rsquo;t be handled very easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four patterns for global state with React hooks: Context or Redux</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/four-patterns-for-global-state-with-react-hooks-context-or-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:50:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/four-patterns-for-global-state-with-react-hooks-context-or-redux/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Global state or shared state is one of the biggest issues when you start developing a React app. Should we use Redux? Do hooks provide a Redux-like solution? I would like to show four patterns toward using Redux. This is my personal opinion and mainly for new apps.
Pattern 1: Prop passing Some might think it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t scale, but the most basic pattern should still be prop passing. If the app is small enough, define local state in a parent component and simply pass it down to child components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing React custom hooks for Redux without react-redux</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/developing-react-custom-hooks-for-redux-without-react-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/developing-react-custom-hooks-for-redux-without-react-redux/</guid>
      <description>Background Ever since I learned Redux, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking an alternative integration of react and redux to the official react-redux library. The intuition behind it is that Redux is super simple which I like a lot, whereas react-redux is complex because of performance tuning. If you are developing a business product, the official react-redux is to go without a doubt, but if you are playing with creating a toy app or you are just starting learning Redux, you might want something more straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A deadly simple React bindings library for Redux with Hooks API</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/a-deadly-simple-react-bindings-library-for-redux-with-hooks-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/a-deadly-simple-react-bindings-library-for-redux-with-hooks-api/</guid>
      <description>There is a follow-up article which describes the implementation details of this library. Please visit here.
 Redux is one of the popular libraries for React. Although Redux itself is not tied to React, it&amp;rsquo;s often used with the official bindings react-redux that allows to connect Redux state to any React components.
In this article, we propose another bindings library to combine React and Redux. This library tries to be simple and easy for beginners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React Hooks Tutorial on pure useReducer &#43; useContext for global state like Redux and comparison with react-hooks-global-state</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-hooks-tutorial-for-pure-usereducer-usecontext-for-global-state-like-redux-and-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-hooks-tutorial-for-pure-usereducer-usecontext-for-global-state-like-redux-and-comparison/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I will first explain minimal code to implement global state with useReducer and useContext which are called &amp;ldquo;hooks&amp;rdquo; that will be available in React 16.7. I will then compare it with react-hooks-global-state which is a tiny library that I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing for global state management primarily for small applications.
Note: Global state is convenient for sharing values among components far apart in the component tree, but it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be abused because it would limit the reusability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React global state by Context API for TypeScript</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-global-state-by-context-api-for-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-global-state-by-context-api-for-typescript/</guid>
      <description>Note: this post has nothing to do with React Hooks API.
In my previous post, I introduced a library called react-context-global-state. After a while, I have better knowlege of TypeScript (yes, I&amp;rsquo;m a beginner!), and come up with fairly good type definitions. I just released a new version.
https://www.npmjs.com/package/react-context-global-state
Example code in TypeScript Let me breifly show how the code looks like in TypeScript.
In a file named state.ts, we define a global state and export function components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redux middleware compatible React Hooks library for easy global state management</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/redux-middleware-compatible-react-hooks-library-for-easy-global-state-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/redux-middleware-compatible-react-hooks-library-for-easy-global-state-management/</guid>
      <description>The library I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing a library to make use of React Hooks API. The library is for global state mangement with the aim to use it instead of Redux, especially for smaller applications. See the repository for more information and the source code.
https://github.com/dai-shi/react-hooks-global-state
Please also check out my previous posts [1] [2].
Support for Redux middleware Originally, the library was extending useState for global state. Later, reducer is supported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An alternative to React Redux by React Hooks API (For both JavaScript and TypeScript)</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/an-alternative-to-react-redux-by-react-hooks-api-for-both-javascript-and-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/an-alternative-to-react-redux-by-react-hooks-api-for-both-javascript-and-typescript/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Everyone is excited about the new React Hooks API. So am I. Having been thinking how to manage global state, the Hooks API seems promising. By the way, I like Redux a lot, but I don&amp;rsquo;t like react-redux a.k.a connect very much. It is too complicated for beginners to use it properly. For example, reselect / memoization is a hard concept to explain. My recommendation is to structure a global state so that mapStateToProps only needs to select a part of the state without any logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript-aware React hooks for global state</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/typescript-aware-react-hooks-for-global-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/typescript-aware-react-hooks-for-global-state/</guid>
      <description>React Hooks API is a new proposal for React v16.7. It enables writing all components as functions with full functionality. You can develop &amp;ldquo;custom hooks&amp;rdquo; to add a new functionality. Although it&amp;rsquo;s not released yet, I would like to introduce a new library to support global state. Note that it&amp;rsquo;s still an experiment.
The library It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;react-hooks-global-state&amp;rdquo; and is available in npm. Please also checkout the GitHub repository.
https://github.com/dai-shi/react-hooks-global-state</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React global state by Context API</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-global-state-by-context-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-global-state-by-context-api/</guid>
      <description>I had been trying to find a way to use React without using class. Redux is one solution to achieve this. Although I love the idea of writing everthing in pure functions, Redux is sometimes not suitable for small apps. React v16.3 introduced new Context API officially. Since then, several ideas were proposed to use it for managing global state. So far, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find something I really liked, hence I made a new one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
