<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fetch on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.axlight.com/tags/fetch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fetch on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.axlight.com/tags/fetch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create React custom hooks for data fetching with useEffect</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-to-create-react-custom-hooks-for-data-fetching-with-useeffect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-to-create-react-custom-hooks-for-data-fetching-with-useeffect/</guid>
      <description>Background React 16.8 added a new API, Hooks. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t learned hooks yet, go to the official site and read the entire document before continuing this article.
https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-intro.html
Hooks are a new addition in React 16.8. They let you use state and other React features without writing a class. This… reactjs.org This article is about how to create custom hooks for data fetching. As described in the roadmap, React is planning to release react-cache and Suspense for data fetching in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>useFetch: React custom hook for Fetch API with Suspense and Concurrent Mode in Mind</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/usefetch-react-custom-hook-for-fetch-api-with-suspense-and-concurrent-mode-in-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/usefetch-react-custom-hook-for-fetch-api-with-suspense-and-concurrent-mode-in-mind/</guid>
      <description>Introduction While I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like coding React without hooks, react-cache still seems to be still far away. Surely, caching in data fetching important, nevertheless I would like to seek possibilities of implementations only with React Hooks. These might be obsoleted in the future, but I want something today, that is &amp;ldquo;useFetch&amp;rdquo;. This could be still useful without react-cache in case sophisticated caching is not necessary.
I&amp;rsquo;ve started developing &amp;ldquo;useFetch&amp;rdquo; as a tutorial to build a custom hook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React Hooks Tutorial on Developing a Custom Hook for Data Fetching</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-hooks-tutorial-on-developing-a-custom-hook-for-data-fetching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-hooks-tutorial-on-developing-a-custom-hook-for-data-fetching/</guid>
      <description>Introduction React Hooks are a new feature coming in React 16.7. It allows us to write stateful function components that were impossible before without class components. The official docs are must-read, so check them out if you haven&amp;rsquo;t.
https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-intro.html
Besides stateful function components, this new feature allow us to build a custom hook to share logic between components. This has been possible with High-order Components (HoCs), and although there&amp;rsquo;s technically no difference what hooks can achieve, hooks simplify it a lot and reduce so called &amp;ldquo;wrapper hell&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>