<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>async on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.axlight.com/tags/async/</link>
    <description>Recent content in async on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 10:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.axlight.com/tags/async/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>React hooks-oriented Redux coding pattern without thunks and action creators</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-hooks-oriented-redux-coding-pattern-without-thunks-and-action-creators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 10:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-hooks-oriented-redux-coding-pattern-without-thunks-and-action-creators/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I love Redux. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I like all parts of Redux ecosystem. Some people dislike Redux because of its boilerplate code. That&amp;rsquo;s sad. Boilerplate code is not from the Redux core, but from the ecosystem. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. Best practices are nice and I think the recent work of Redux Starter Kit is great. (Claps to Mark)
I think I have my own understanding of how to use Redux with React.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create React custom hooks for data fetching with useEffect</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-to-create-react-custom-hooks-for-data-fetching-with-useeffect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-to-create-react-custom-hooks-for-data-fetching-with-useeffect/</guid>
      <description>Background React 16.8 added a new API, Hooks. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t learned hooks yet, go to the official site and read the entire document before continuing this article.
https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-intro.html
Hooks are a new addition in React 16.8. They let you use state and other React features without writing a class. This… reactjs.org This article is about how to create custom hooks for data fetching. As described in the roadmap, React is planning to release react-cache and Suspense for data fetching in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>useFetch: React custom hook for Fetch API with Suspense and Concurrent Mode in Mind</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/usefetch-react-custom-hook-for-fetch-api-with-suspense-and-concurrent-mode-in-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/usefetch-react-custom-hook-for-fetch-api-with-suspense-and-concurrent-mode-in-mind/</guid>
      <description>Introduction While I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like coding React without hooks, react-cache still seems to be still far away. Surely, caching in data fetching important, nevertheless I would like to seek possibilities of implementations only with React Hooks. These might be obsoleted in the future, but I want something today, that is &amp;ldquo;useFetch&amp;rdquo;. This could be still useful without react-cache in case sophisticated caching is not necessary.
I&amp;rsquo;ve started developing &amp;ldquo;useFetch&amp;rdquo; as a tutorial to build a custom hook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing React custom hooks for abortable async functions with AbortController</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/developing-react-custom-hooks-for-abortable-async-functions-with-abortcontroller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/developing-react-custom-hooks-for-abortable-async-functions-with-abortcontroller/</guid>
      <description>In my previous article, I introduced how the custom hook useAsyncTask handles async functions with AbortController and demonstrated a typeahead search example. In this article, I explain about the implementation of useAsyncTask.
Recap JavaScript promise is not abortable. The fetch API is based on promise, and hence you can&amp;rsquo;t cancel it in pure JavaScript. To cancel fetch, the DOM spec introduced AbortController. The AbortController is a general interface and not specific to fetch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to abortable async functions for React with hooks</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/introduction-to-abortable-async-functions-for-react-with-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 10:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/introduction-to-abortable-async-functions-for-react-with-hooks/</guid>
      <description>There is a follow-up article which describes the implementation details of the library. Please visit here.
 TL;DR Just visit the example in codesandbox and try it.
Background You can&amp;rsquo;t cancel promises in JavaScript and that&amp;rsquo;s one of the reason why libraries such as redux-saga and redux-observables are popular because they allow cancellation. While they are good solutions as well as Redux is, there might be a case when you want just a cancellation mechanism for a promise, not the entire framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React Hooks Tutorial on Developing a Custom Hook for Data Fetching</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-hooks-tutorial-on-developing-a-custom-hook-for-data-fetching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-hooks-tutorial-on-developing-a-custom-hook-for-data-fetching/</guid>
      <description>Introduction React Hooks are a new feature coming in React 16.7. It allows us to write stateful function components that were impossible before without class components. The official docs are must-read, so check them out if you haven&amp;rsquo;t.
https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-intro.html
Besides stateful function components, this new feature allow us to build a custom hook to share logic between components. This has been possible with High-order Components (HoCs), and although there&amp;rsquo;s technically no difference what hooks can achieve, hooks simplify it a lot and reduce so called &amp;ldquo;wrapper hell&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>