<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>signals on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.axlight.com/tags/signals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in signals on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 21:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.axlight.com/tags/signals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why You Don&#39;t Need Signals in React</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/why-you-dont-need-signals-in-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 21:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/why-you-dont-need-signals-in-react/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the world of web frontend development, signals have become a popular topic. At their core, signals are used to represent changes in state over time. Some developers have discussed the potential of using signals in conjunction with React.
Signals are actually an older concept, and it&amp;rsquo;s uncertain how they are understood by modern web developers. Initially, I was confused about the characteristics of signals, but I later realized that they can be boiled down to two main aspects:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Create React Signals Internals</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/demystifying-create-react-signals-internals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 23:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/demystifying-create-react-signals-internals/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When I first saw SolidJS and Preact Signals, I thought they are interesting but they are different from React. What made me motivated is @preact/signals-react. I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the original implementation using REACT INTERNALS, and that drove me to create something.
We already had Jotai. Jotai atoms are like signals, representing reactive sources, and allowing to form a dependency graph or a data flow. The missing piece was signal-like syntax without hooks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
