<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>react on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.axlight.com/tags/react/</link>
    <description>Recent content in react on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.axlight.com/tags/react/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An alternative to React Redux by React Hooks API (For both JavaScript and TypeScript)</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/an-alternative-to-react-redux-by-react-hooks-api-for-both-javascript-and-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/an-alternative-to-react-redux-by-react-hooks-api-for-both-javascript-and-typescript/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Everyone is excited about the new React Hooks API. So am I. Having been thinking how to manage global state, the Hooks API seems promising. By the way, I like Redux a lot, but I don&amp;rsquo;t like react-redux a.k.a connect very much. It is too complicated for beginners to use it properly. For example, reselect / memoization is a hard concept to explain. My recommendation is to structure a global state so that mapStateToProps only needs to select a part of the state without any logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript-aware React hooks for global state</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/typescript-aware-react-hooks-for-global-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/typescript-aware-react-hooks-for-global-state/</guid>
      <description>React Hooks API is a new proposal for React v16.7. It enables writing all components as functions with full functionality. You can develop &amp;ldquo;custom hooks&amp;rdquo; to add a new functionality. Although it&amp;rsquo;s not released yet, I would like to introduce a new library to support global state. Note that it&amp;rsquo;s still an experiment.
The library It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;react-hooks-global-state&amp;rdquo; and is available in npm. Please also checkout the GitHub repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React global state by Context API</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-global-state-by-context-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/react-global-state-by-context-api/</guid>
      <description>I had been trying to find a way to use React without using class. Redux is one solution to achieve this. Although I love the idea of writing everthing in pure functions, Redux is sometimes not suitable for small apps. React v16.3 introduced new Context API officially. Since then, several ideas were proposed to use it for managing global state. So far, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find something I really liked, hence I made a new one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>