<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abortable on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.axlight.com/tags/abortable/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abortable on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.axlight.com/tags/abortable/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to create React custom hooks for data fetching with useEffect</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-to-create-react-custom-hooks-for-data-fetching-with-useeffect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-to-create-react-custom-hooks-for-data-fetching-with-useeffect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;React 16.8 added a new API, Hooks. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t learned hooks yet, go to the official site and read the entire document before continuing this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-intro.html&#34;&gt;https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-intro.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hooks are a new addition in React 16.8. They let you use state and other React features without writing a class. This…&#xA;reactjs.org&#xA;This article is about how to create custom hooks for data fetching. As described in &lt;a href=&#34;https://reactjs.org/blog/2018/11/27/react-16-roadmap.html&#34;&gt;the roadmap&lt;/a&gt;, React is planning to release react-cache and Suspense for data fetching in the near future. This is going to be a standard way of data fetching in React, however, data fetching with useEffect is still useful in certain use cases where the lifecycle of fetched data is the same as that of components. In such use cases, caching is not important and we can safely store fetched data in a component local state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing React custom hooks for abortable async functions with AbortController</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/developing-react-custom-hooks-for-abortable-async-functions-with-abortcontroller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/developing-react-custom-hooks-for-abortable-async-functions-with-abortcontroller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.axlight.com/posts/introduction-to-abortable-async-functions-for-react-with-hooks/&#34;&gt;my previous article&lt;/a&gt;, I introduced how the custom hook &lt;code&gt;useAsyncTask&lt;/code&gt; handles async functions with AbortController and demonstrated a typeahead search example. In this article, I explain about the implementation of &lt;code&gt;useAsyncTask&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;recap&#34;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JavaScript promise is not abortable. The fetch API is based on promise, and hence you can&amp;rsquo;t cancel it in pure JavaScript. To cancel &lt;code&gt;fetch&lt;/code&gt;, the DOM spec introduced &lt;code&gt;AbortController&lt;/code&gt;. The AbortController is a general interface and not specific to &lt;code&gt;fetch&lt;/code&gt;. Technically, we can use it to cancel promises, and it would be nice to have an easy way to handle abortable async functions. In the React world, we are expecting the Hooks API soon. I&amp;rsquo;ve started a project to implement custom hooks for abortable async functions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to abortable async functions for React with hooks</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/introduction-to-abortable-async-functions-for-react-with-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 10:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/introduction-to-abortable-async-functions-for-react-with-hooks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a follow-up article which describes the implementation details of the library. Please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.axlight.com/posts/developing-react-custom-hooks-for-abortable-async-functions-with-abortcontroller/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://codesandbox.io/s/github/dai-shi/react-hooks-async/tree/master/examples/04_typeahead&#34;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt; in codesandbox and try it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t cancel promises in JavaScript and that&amp;rsquo;s one of the reason why libraries such as redux-saga and redux-observables are popular because they allow cancellation. While they are good solutions as well as Redux is, there might be a case when you want just a cancellation mechanism for a promise, not the entire framework. As is noted JavaScript doesn&amp;rsquo;t have cancellation mechanism, but DOM has it. It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/AbortController&#34;&gt;AbortController&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s only supported in recent browsers, but polyfills should help for old browsers and Node.js.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
