<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>abortable on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.axlight.com/tags/abortable/</link>
    <description>Recent content in abortable on Daishi Kato&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.axlight.com/tags/abortable/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to create React custom hooks for data fetching with useEffect</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-to-create-react-custom-hooks-for-data-fetching-with-useeffect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/how-to-create-react-custom-hooks-for-data-fetching-with-useeffect/</guid>
      <description>Background React 16.8 added a new API, Hooks. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t learned hooks yet, go to the official site and read the entire document before continuing this article.&#xA;https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-intro.html&#xA;Hooks are a new addition in React 16.8. They let you use state and other React features without writing a class. This… reactjs.org This article is about how to create custom hooks for data fetching. As described in the roadmap, React is planning to release react-cache and Suspense for data fetching in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing React custom hooks for abortable async functions with AbortController</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/developing-react-custom-hooks-for-abortable-async-functions-with-abortcontroller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/developing-react-custom-hooks-for-abortable-async-functions-with-abortcontroller/</guid>
      <description>In my previous article, I introduced how the custom hook useAsyncTask handles async functions with AbortController and demonstrated a typeahead search example. In this article, I explain about the implementation of useAsyncTask.&#xA;Recap JavaScript promise is not abortable. The fetch API is based on promise, and hence you can&amp;rsquo;t cancel it in pure JavaScript. To cancel fetch, the DOM spec introduced AbortController. The AbortController is a general interface and not specific to fetch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to abortable async functions for React with hooks</title>
      <link>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/introduction-to-abortable-async-functions-for-react-with-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 10:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.axlight.com/posts/introduction-to-abortable-async-functions-for-react-with-hooks/</guid>
      <description>There is a follow-up article which describes the implementation details of the library. Please visit here.&#xA;TL;DR Just visit the example in codesandbox and try it.&#xA;Background You can&amp;rsquo;t cancel promises in JavaScript and that&amp;rsquo;s one of the reason why libraries such as redux-saga and redux-observables are popular because they allow cancellation. While they are good solutions as well as Redux is, there might be a case when you want just a cancellation mechanism for a promise, not the entire framework.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
